Tej Chajed

Curriculum Vitae

☎ +1 (217) 840-0140 ⋈ tchajed@mit.edu 1 https://chajed.io

Research Interests

I work on formal verification for systems software. In my research I develop **realistic**, **performant systems**, specify their intended behavior, then prove that the implementation always meet the specification. My PhD research culminated in a **verified**, **concurrent file system** with a proof that your data is safe if the computer suddenly reboots, and which gets good performance.

Education

2014–2022 Ph.D. in Computer Science, MIT, Cambridge, MA.

(expected) Verifying a concurrent, crash-safe file system with sequential reasoning

2014–2017 M.S. in Computer Science, GPA: 4.0/4.0, MIT, Cambridge, MA. Verifying an I/O-concurrent file system

2010–2014 **B.S. in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science**, GPA: 3.97/4.0, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL.

Research Experiences

2014—present **Research assistant**, at MIT in the PDOS group. advised by Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich, and Joseph Tassarotti

2013–2014 **Undergraduate researcher**, at University of Illinois in the DPRG group. advised by Indranil Gupta

Draft papers

draft 2022 Reasoning about ownership and asynchrony for crash-safety in separation logic

Joseph Tassarotti, Tej Chajed, Ralf Jung, Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich

Conference Publications

OSDI 2022 Verifying the DaisyNFS concurrent and crash-safe file system with sequential reasoning

 $\it Tej\ Chajed,$ Joseph Tassarotti, Mark Theng, Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich

OSDI 2021 **GoJournal: a verified, concurrent, crash-safe journaling system**Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, Mark Theng, Ralf Jung, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich

SOSP 2019 Verifying concurrent, crash-safe systems with Perennial Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich

- Security 2019 EverParse: Verified Secure Zero-Copy Parsers for Authenticated Message Formats
 - Tahina Ramananandro, Antoine Delignat-Lavaud, Cédric Fournet, Nikhil Swamy, *Tej Chajed*, Nadim Kobeissi, Jonathan Protzenko
 - PLDI 2019 **Argosy: Verifying Layered Storage Systems with Recovery Refinement** *Tej Chajed*, Joseph Tassarotti, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich
 - OSDI 2018 Verifying concurrent software using movers in CSPEC Tej Chajed, M. Frans Kaashoek, Butler Lampson, and Nickolai Zeldovich
 - OSDI 2018 **Proving confidentiality in a file system using DiskSec**Atalay İleri, *Tej Chajed*, Adam Chlipala, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich
 - SOSP 2017 Verifying a high-performance crash-safe file system using a tree specification
 Haogang Chen, *Tej Chajed*, Alex Konradi, Stephanie Wang, Atalay İleri, Adam Chlipala,
 M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich
 - SOSP 2015 Using Crash Hoare Logic for certifying the FSCQ file system
 Haogang Chen, Daniel Ziegler, *Tej Chajed*, Adam Chlipala, M. Frans Kaashoek, and
 Nickolai Zeldovich
 - SoCC 2013 Natjam: design and evaluation of eviction policies for supporting priorities and deadlines in mapreduce clusters

 Brian Cho, Muntasir Rahman, *Tej Chajed*, Indranil Gupta, Cristina Abad, Nathan Roberts, Philbert Lin

Workshop Papers

- CoqPL 2021 Record Updates in Coq Tej Chajed
- CoqPL 2020 Verifying concurrent Go code in Coq with Goose

 Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich
- HotOS 2015 **Amber: Decoupling user data from web applications**Tej Chajed, Jon Gjengset, Jelle van den Hooff, M. Frans Kaashoek, James Mickens, Robert Morris, Nickolai Zeldovich

Teaching Experiences

- Fall 2020 TA, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT.
- Fall 2019 TA, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT.
- Fall 2017 TA, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT.
- Spring 2017 Course development, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT.

 During this time I designed and implemented the programming assignments for 6.826.

Mentorship

- 2022 Mark Theng (master's thesis)
- 2021 Sharon Lin, undergrad
- 2020 Sydney Gibson (master's thesis)

- 2019 Eleftherios Ionnidis (<u>master's thesis</u>)
 2017 Alex Konradi (<u>master's thesis</u>)
 2017 Daniel Ziegler (<u>master's thesis</u>)

 Industry Experience
- ${\bf Summer} \quad {\bf Research \ Intern}, \, {\bf Microsoft \ Research}, \, {\bf Cambridge}, \, {\bf UK}.$
 - 2017 Verifying low-level parsing in F*, with Cédric Fournet
- Summer **Software Engineering Intern**, Google, Zürich, Switzerland. 2014

Honors & Awards

- 2014–2019 NSF Graduate Research Fellowship
 - 2014 Jacobs Presidential Fellowship
- 2010–2014 Chancellor's Scholar

Professional Service

- PLDI 2022 Program Committee
- POPL 2022 Artifact Evaluation Committee
- POPL 2021 Organized a tutorial "Iris A Modular Foundation for Higher-Order Concurrent Separation Logic"
 - EuroDW EuroSys Doctoral Workshop, PC

2021

- POPL 2021 Artifact Evaluation Committee
- PLDI 2020 Artifact Evaluation Committee
- POPL 2020 Artifact Evaluation Committee
- SOSP 2019 Artifact Evaluation Committee

References

Frans Kaashoek kaashoek@mit.edu

Nickolai Zeldovich

nickolai@csail.mit.edu

Joseph Tassarotti

joseph.tassarotti@bc.edu